I know exactly what
I'm gonna eat today!
我确切地知道什么
今天我要吃饭！
Wait, why did I come in here, again?
等等，我怎么又进来了？
- Lemme guess--
- Don't tell me.
- 让我猜猜--
- 别告诉我。
Hmm, starts with a K.
嗯，以 K 开头。
Uhh--
呃——
♪ Throwin' patties
on the grill ♪
♪ 扔肉饼
在烤架上♪
♪ Juggling ingredients ♪
- Ow, ow!
♪ 杂耍配料 ♪
- 噢，噢！
♪ Trying not to spill ♪
♪ 尽量不要洒出来 ♪
♪ The grill aflame ♪
♪ 烤架着火了 ♪
♪ Work is a game ♪
♪ 工作就是一场游戏 ♪
♪ When I'm done,
you'll have a bun ♪
♪ 当我完成后
你会得到一个小圆面包♪
♪ Full of yum, yum, yum ♪
♪ 充满美味，美味，美味 ♪
Huh?
啊？
Yes!
是的！
My plan is working perfectly.
我的计划正在完美地进行。
Minus the third degree burns.
减去三度烧伤。
Ooh!
哦！
Ahh!
啊！
And now, for my clever escape.
现在，为了我巧妙的逃脱。
Hey! Where do you think
you're going?
嘿！你认为哪里
你要去吗？
- Ahh!
- Trying to sneak out
- 啊！
- 试图溜出去
before the big delivery, huh?
在大发货之前吧？
No need to get cold feet,
little patty.
无需临阵退缩，
小帕蒂。
You'll be very happy
in your new home.
你会很高兴的
在你的新家。
Oh, no!
哦，不！
I'm gonna be late
for my delivery!
我要迟到了
为了我的交货！
Whoop!
哎哟！
Don't worry, little patty,
you're almost home.
别担心，小帕蒂
你快到家了。
Huh? Ohh!
啊？哦！
Wait!
等待！
Whoa!
哇！
Ohh!
哦！
Whoa!
哇！
Hey, something soft
broke my fall.
嘿，软软的东西
打破了我的跌倒。
Thanks, patty.
谢谢，帕蒂。
Patty,
帕蒂，
I don't think
we're in Bikini Bottom anymore.
我不认为
我们已经在比基尼泳裤了。
We must be lost
in the deep Goo Sea.
我们一定会迷失
在咕海深处。
I guess we'll miss
the delivery.
我想我们会错过
交货。
I've let down
poor, old Mr. Krabs.
我已经失望了
可怜的老蟹先生。
Hey, where are you going?
嘿，你要去哪里？
I'm just going to the, uh...
我只是要去，呃...
little patty's room?
小帕蒂的房间？
Oh, why didn't you say so?
哦，你为什么不这么说？
I'll discreetly turn around
and give you a little privacy.
我会小心翼翼地转身
并给你一点隐私。
Hey, wait a minute.
嘿，等一下。
I don't make little patties.
我不做小馅饼。
Nice try, Plankton.
不错的尝试，浮游生物。
Get back here.
回到这里吧。
Wait a minute,
we're marooned!
等一下，
我们被困了！
We have to make
this patty last.
我们必须做
最后这个肉饼。
It's our only food
until we're rescued.
这是我们唯一的食物
直到我们获救。
So?
What's your point?
所以？
你的观点是什么？
If we're gonna survive,
we'll have to share.
如果我们要活下去
我们必须分享。
Huh, share?
呵呵，分享一下？
You've got yourself a deal,
big boy!
你已经和自己达成了协议，
大男孩！
Aww, put 'er there, pal.
哇，把它放在那里，朋友。
Here, you can have
the first bite.
在这里，你可以拥有
第一口。
Make it a small one.
让它变小一点。
Don't mind if I do.
如果我这样做的话，请不要介意。
That's strange.
这很奇怪。
Uh, Plankton?
呃，浮游生物？
This patty tastes
a little... angry.
这个饼的味道
有点……生气。
Plankton.
浮游生物。
Whaa!
哇！
Whoa-oh!
哇哦！
Plankton!
You're okay!
浮游生物！
你没事吧！
Oh, I thought I lost you.
哦，我以为我失去了你。
Uhh, SpongeBob?
呃，海绵宝宝？
Whoa!
哇！
Ahh! Ahh! Ahh!
啊！啊！啊！
Ahh!
啊！
Enough!
足够的！
Sorry.
对不起。
We have to start looking for
shelter before it gets dark.
我们必须开始寻找
天黑之前避难。
What about Mr. Snake Monster?
蛇怪先生呢？
Can he come stay with us?
他能来和我们一起住吗？
No.
不。
Sorry. I tried.
对不起。我试过。
Not too shabby.
不太破旧。
Yep.
是的。
Plankton, could you move
your leg over a little?
浮游生物，你能动一下吗
你的腿有点过了吗？
It's a bit cramped in here.
这里有点局促。
Hey, lucky these thorns
broke our fall.
嘿，幸运的是这些荆棘
打破了我们的跌倒。
Yeah, lucky me.
是的，我很幸运。
Hey, this place looks
pretty spacious.
嘿，这个地方看起来
相当宽敞。
We can really do a lot
with this place.
我们真的可以做很多
与这个地方。
Over there can be your room.
那边可能是你的房间。
That could be my room.
那可能是我的房间。
Oh, it's a little dark
back here, isn't it?
哦，有点暗
回到这里，不是吗？
Hey, I can hear my echo.
嘿，我能听到我的回声。
Does it feel a little
wet in here to you?
是不是感觉有点
你这里湿了吗？
Hey, look.
I found a light switch.
嘿，看。
我找到了一个电灯开关。
Oh, hey, Plankton.
哦，嘿，浮游生物。
New plan.
新计划。
Let's grab a bite to eat.
我们去吃点东西吧。
Ooh, look! Bananers!
哦，看！香蕉！
Hmm.
唔。
Gah. Wha!
嘎。世界卫生大会！
Finally, some grub!
最后，一些幼虫！
Let's eat.
我们吃饭吧。
Mama!
妈妈！
both: Aww!
两人：哇！
Gah!
嘎！
Uhh.
呃。
Oh!
哦！
Should we eat this rock?
我们应该吃这块石头吗？
I'll eat anything.
我什么都吃。
Ohh!
哦！
Leave us alone!
别管我们了！
Hey!
嘿！
both: Aha!
两人：啊哈！
Mmm.
嗯。
Hup!
both: Ah!
哈！
两人：啊！
- Hup!
- Yeah!
- 哈！
- 是的！
Great work out there today.
今天的表现很棒。
Ohh, it's just not the same
without you.
哦，只是不一样
没有你。
It's just not the
same without you.
这只是不是
没有你也一样。
SpongeBob?
- Yes, Plankton?
海绵宝宝？
- 是的，浮游生物？
Are you thinkin'
what I'm thinkin'?
你在想吗
我在想什么？
Yep, I can't decide either.
是的，我也无法决定。
Do the company sports jerseys
look better in beige or green?
公司有运动衫吗
米色或绿色更好看？
No, you imbecile.
不，你这个白痴。
It's time for us to am-scray
and get back home
是时候让我们开始尖叫了
然后回家
without the monsters noticing.
在怪物不注意的情况下。
They're watching us everywhere, Plankton.
他们到处监视着我们，浮游生物。
Run for it!
奔跑吧！
Yah! Nose dive!
啊！鼻子俯冲！
both: Whoa, whoa, whoa!
两人：哇哇哇！
Too many monsters!
怪物太多了！
Ahh!
啊！
SpongeBob, I have an idea.
海绵宝宝，我有一个主意。
Follow my lead.
跟随我的引导。
All right, monsters.
好吧，怪物们。
We'll go back to work and whip
up some nice coconut patties.
我们会回去工作并鞭打
一些美味的椰子馅饼。
In fact, we have a big,
delicious surprise for you.
事实上，我们有一个很大的，
给你美味的惊喜。
You just have to
close your eyes.
你只需要
闭上你的眼睛。
Good! Now stick your fingers
in your ears and sing,
好的！现在伸出你的手指
在你耳边歌唱，
♪ La la la la
la la la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦
啦啦啦♪
all: ♪ La la la la
la la la ♪
全体：♪ 啦啦啦啦
啦啦啦♪
Now, run!
现在，跑吧！
both: Whoa!
两人：哇！
Yeah!
是的！
Ahh.
啊。
Goodbye, friends
who kept us captive
再见，朋友们
谁囚禁了我们
by threatening to eat us!
威胁要吃掉我们！
Great thinking back there, Plankton.
浮游生物，你的想法很棒。
How about we celebrate
our victory?
我们庆祝一下怎么样
我们的胜利？
both: Cheers!
两人：干杯！
Hm, wait. Why are we heading
back to the island?
嗯，等等。我们为何前进
回岛了？
I think the island
is heading back to us.
我认为岛
正在返回我们身边。
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
Ahh!
啊！
Comin' through!
来了！
- Hm?
- Ahh!
- 嗯？
- 啊！
Ohh!
哦！
Hm? Phew.
嗯？唷。
That was a close one.
那是一场很接近的比赛。
You're late, SpongeBob.
你迟到了，海绵宝宝。
Where have you been
the last six years?
你去哪儿了
过去六年？
Mr. Krabs!
蟹老板！
Well, it was nice
while it lasted.
嗯，很好
当它持续的时候。
It's an earthquake!
Run for your lives!
这是地震！
为你的生命而奔跑！
Ahh!
Oh, ohh!
啊！
哦，哦！
No! Not me restaurant!
不！不是我的餐厅！
I know what I want
to eat today!
我知道我想要什么
今天吃饭！
I'll have one coco patty.
我要一份可可馅饼。
Comin' right up,
for a nominal service charge.
马上就来了，
收取象征性的服务费。
All's well
that ends well, eh, Plankton?
一切都好
结局很好，嗯，浮游生物？
Oh, no!
哦，不！
Where's Plankton?
浮游生物在哪里？
Rawr, rawr,
we're alone at last.
拉尔，拉尔，
我们终于孤独了。
Muah.
么么哒。